My eyes. Or both my legs. Or half my internal organs. I've heard there have been some blind cave raiders. Maybe if it was just one eye. Both legs. I could have Reg carry me on his back. Internal organs. I don't know of any that aren't really necessary.
Okay. I've decided. If you can make it hurt as little as possible, then... Kaja!
If anything is taken, it is over. Kaja has seen many times.
But this is Nanachi! I'm not gonna leave Nanachi!
Nanachi?
You must not, Riko. If you end up helpless like this as well, then it's over. Please, just let me be...
Nanachi!
Forgive me. I'm sorry. I'm fine staying here with Midi.
There's no way this is fine! Nanachi! Nanachi! Let's head to the bottom of the netherworld! Alone with Midi! Come on! Wake up, Nanachi! You can't do this! Come on! Nanachi!
You can't do it!
To be continued...
...and why is it sniffing me?
Hey, Riko!
So, do you have any idea how I... I can get Nanachi back?
Let's see...
Uh...
Oh, yeah, it's happening, Riko.
A big one's here right now. It's the luring.
So, this is it?
Come with me.
Okay. More importantly, I have to get Nanachi out of there somehow!
What is that?
Well, where should I even begin?
Let's see now.
The residents of this village, the Holos, they can't go outside the village, you see.
That's why they lure in a creature from outside and hunt it like this.
It's the only way.
Also, it increases the total value of the village and enriches it.
Uh-huh.
But it looks like they're the ones getting slaughtered down there instead.
Sure looks that way, huh?
Wow, that's the truth anyway.
Oh, it's going the other way now.
What?
Hey now, where are you going?
See where it's headed?
Right towards Prushka!
Oh, Prushka! Another friend of yours?
A very precious friend!
Ah!
Uh, hang on!
Wait a second!
Nanachi, please stay safe until I get back.
Sorry, but, uh, it's Prushka.
We need to get Prushka somewhere safe, quickly!
Ooh!
Uh...
Prushka!
I can't...
feel you so clearly.
Oh, look at that.
Meribututo.
An instrument made from a person.
Ah!
Uh...
Huh?
One loop?
Huh? What was that?
He said to...
take it.
Kyushii, mesho, medifu.
He took the insignia.
And carved it into an instrument.
It is a stone of very precious value.
But he can't bring out that value more than he already has.
He's giving it to you.
Mr. Dieter Soap.
Take it and go from here.
And I think I might agree with him.
But you need to get to someplace safe, too!
No!
Huh?
Rico, Poriun, the jeweler, is the workshop itself.
Cannot move.
That stone...
It insists...
on being with you.
Hmm...
Huh?
Tindefachтакum.
Shaccumodununa.
Nuna.
Keoe...
Medibu...
Pudda...
Sababutsa?
What's happening?
That wound, Kaja remembers. This one came before.
It did?
It underwent much balancing of values, but escaped the village before being whittled away.
But Curious was never this large before, though.
So it's acquired a taste for hollows.
Oh no, it's heading for the market!
Jorohimo with the three sages.
Jorohimo?
So that's who's taking on the role now.
Jorohimo has revealed the great sword Kaja has not seen for a long time.
Uh, it looks super sticky.
It melted!
But, um, will it still be all right?
This is looking bad.
The great sword is not working well. It should be able to emit an ancient power.
An ancient power?
It is crammed and crowded. The sword cannot be used.
Well, aren't the two other sages going to come?
They will not appear unless the membrane is broken.
Then what about that one?
Jorohimo values strenuous activity.
If the prey looks strong, he comes out on his own.
Well, if it isn't Riko.
Oh, hey, you're the owner of the restaurant.
Did you say owner?
My name is Mugi, by the way.
More importantly, what are you doing here? It's dangerous.
What about you, Mugi? I mean, shouldn't you be somewhere safe?
Well, Riko, I'm not here all by myself.
The market is our greatest treasure.
We can't afford to just let that thing try to destroy it.
Fashion dinner!
Hurry up and run, Riko.
If you head up, you're less likely to get hit.
But Mugi, come on.
Isn't there something I can do to help you defeat that thing?
Sure is.
Make sure you don't get eaten by that creature.
Use your value for the robot and that fluffy one.
You mustn't meet your end in this place, Riko.
That big jellyfish creature came here before!
There's gotta be some way to deal with it, right?
Well, no one can leave the village once they've entered it.
Plus, we don't even know what kind of creature that thing is.
Wait, seriously?
Sorry, did I say something wrong?
I wasn't talking about you.
Is it true that no one knows anything about that creature?
That thing is a force field, Sensei Morgan, isn't it?
And those five cylinders must be eyes.
And it's body.
It's floating even without the force field.
So that means...
Hey, Maji Kaja!
Maji?
There's something I want you to get ready for me!
Right now!
He stopped moving all together.
I guess it must be over now.
It's headed for the market.
Guess that makes sense.
Probably wants to feed on some of the smaller ones.
Okay, so...
I need to let Riko know.
No.
Frank!
Thanks so much!
Okay, Maji Kaja, are you ready?
Indemain.
Kaja also received a tuft of hair.
So long as there is value, Kaja can use a fast body and be reckless.
It's here.
Hey!
There's something super delicious right over here!
Now that it's up close, I can see how huge it is.
Do we even have a chance against something like that?
Kaja, go!
Kaja, watch out behind you!
Great job, Kaja!
Kaja, merely slip and fall.
Like I thought, this game won't quit.
Alright then.
Up ahead!
Is that it, Kaja?
I am.
That should do it.
What's that?
A second one?
No, it's a mirror.
Oh wait.
It's like it's intimidating itself.
Do it now!
Rahaaase!
Do it now yeah.
I get it...
If you need one hit, please.
Well...
Lified hit!
're there.
Arras!
That's the throw!
Ah!
No!
Ma?
Ma!
Wiko?
Mookie!
I'm glad you're okay!
Thanks to you.
You know, I heard that this was all you're doing.
I just asked the others to help me out with something, that's all.
That creature, let's just call it Ogastomy for now...
Was floating even though the force field isn't present here,
So I figured its body was lighter than air.
Right.
If it's that big and still lighter than air,
I thought maybe we could catch it with wind.
And though it's hard to continually produce strong wind in static weather,
a fire will last a while before it dies.
So I asked for anyone who's good with fire.
Oh.
You never know by looking at you, but you think a lot, Rico.
That's pretty impressive.
But unfortunately, I see you cut your precious air.
You need to use stuff like that for yourself.
Our leader, Judo, told us,
we cave raiders have to take an eye for an eye.
Your leader?
Whenever us cave raiders are saved, then we go and save others.
That way, there's a chance we might be on the receiving end of such a deed.
So there's an ulterior motive.
It's partially for my own sake.
Some might even call it unethical.
Hmm. Well, that's okay, Rico.
And the residents here aren't that soft, you know.
Wait. What?
Everybody run!
No!
Call me. Call me, Riko.
Sorry I kept you waiting. Riko, tell me what to do next.
Uh, how did...
All these thoughts came flooding in. And scenery, feelings...
Riko, you and Pruska called and I knew instantly. Amazing.
That's a white whistle's power.
The timber of the instrument also has the power to draw out the true purpose within all relics.
Pruska...
All right, let's go!
Roger that.
Eliminate all of the tentacles in my path.
Take the most direct route without using my incinerator.
Take it down!
Uh, Riko? It's already just an empty shell over here.
What?
Hadi?
Is the party already over?
Oh, I was wanting to see you in action.
Is it time for the applause?
Did that part already happen?
Or is it time to start cleaning up?
Ooh, the queen is already dead.
Hadi!
You can let everyone else handle the remaining males.
They can't really grow big enough in here to make a new queen.
New queen?
Fuzo Shepu.
You see, that is not a single creature.
It's actually a large nest of smaller beings.
This transparent one is a male.
Ow!
Ooh!
They gather together and move around as a group in order to hunt.
But since the queen is dead, the remaining ones have divided up and left to create a new one.
So well done!
Good job!
Honey!
If you knew that already, then you should have told us before now, okay?
Well, everyone loves a festival.
After all, the villagers can't leave this place.
See?
Just look at that.
All those satisfied faces.
So, um, if you know, please tell me.
Is there any way to get Nanachi back from that other sage?
Hmm, let's see.
If you could get even just a part of Fopta, the embodiment of value, perhaps...
Fopta?
Meh.
I doubt that's possible, though.
Good luck!
So wait, Nanachi is stuck there and can't leave?
Belov told us that in order to make a trade, we would need value that was equal or greater to that of a human child.
We need Fopta.
Um, so, Reg, what's Fopta like, anyway?
We met and had a talk of sorts, but I don't know much.
Riko, I should probably leave and find Fopta again.
I'm not sure how it'll turn out, but we won't get anywhere like this.
Hey, Riko?
What exactly is Fopta?
The embodiment of value and the thing we all most desire, but also we most fear.
You most fear?
What do you mean?
Well, you see...
Wait, first of all.
Who in the world are you supposed to be?
You know what?
A long time's passed since I found myself here, and I've never once seen you before.
Because I never smell you before.
Hey, um, so, Mugi, Riko is the one from Dogupu who I...
Uh, sorry, it's fine.
It's just that, if they catch me, I'll never be able to tell my story, right?
I am one of the survivors of the Suicide Squad Ganja.
We went on an expedition in search of the Golden City in the depths of the Netherworld.
I was in charge of managing relics and the health of our companions.
My name is Vuedo Errico, and I was one of the three sages.
You wanted to know more about Fopta, right?
Please!
I've honestly never had an audience with the princess, but I know their desires, and what it is they want most of all.
If I tell you everything that I know, there's probably no turning back from it, Riko.
I'm not the type to say I don't wanna, or else I wouldn't be here!
First of all, they say that time here is out of sync with the rest of the outside world,
so I'm not exactly sure how long ago this would be in terms of your own time.
I don't know if you sent these children.
That boy must be what you talked about, a true resident of the Golden City.
So, Idomyui, did you see it?
The way Wazukyan's face looked, he can still get that scared, huh?
My dear Idomyui, your existence, your desires, your memories, the time has now come to dredge all that up.
Thank you.